<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on </title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 18:24:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Hello world!</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=1/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 18:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=1/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>GPT Mouse</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=898/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 08:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=898/</guid>
        <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image size-large&#34;&gt;[&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;2048&#34; height=&#34;2048&#34; src=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-2.png?w=1024&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-900&#34; srcset=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-2.png 2048w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-2-300x300.png 300w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-2-1024x1024.png 1024w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-2-150x150.png 150w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-2-768x768.png 768w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-2-1536x1536.png 1536w&#34; sizes=&#34;auto, (max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In an era where the marvels of Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) had redefined the boundaries of possibility, there lived two mice, each a testament to the divergent paths of fortune and fancy. The City Mouse resided in a domain where technology and opulence melded into a dazzling tableau, while the Country Mouse dwelled in the gentle embrace of a timeless pastoral idyll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the heart of the city, the home of the City Mouse was a spectacle of grandeur. The dining chamber was a cornucopia of gastronomic delights, arrayed with dishes that would make a connoisseur’s heart leap. Here, molecular gastronomy created cheese that sang with the flavors of distant lands, and pastries that dissolved into symphonies of sweetness on the tongue. Jellies shimmered like precious gems, each a burst of perfected taste crafted by the genius of AGI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For entertainment, the City Mouse had at his disposal virtual realms where fantasies became indistinguishable from reality. He journeyed through digital landscapes where he could scamper alongside legendary heroes of mouse folklore, or partake in banquets rivaling those of mouse kings of yore. In these realms, every adventure, every thrill was but a thought away, bound only by the limits of imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In matters of health and longevity, the City Mouse was graced with the elixirs of life itself. AGI-driven medicine provided not only cure but prevention, a shield against the ravages of time and disease. His body, rejuvenated by cellular repair technologies, was a testament to the age of amortality, a life where the ticking of the clock held no sway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the realm of education and science, the City Mouse had access to the sum of mouse knowledge. Libraries of information were available in an instant, offering wisdom spanning from the intricacies of cheese aging to the mysteries of the cosmos. His mind, ever hungry for knowledge, feasted on these intellectual banquets, each morsel of information a jewel of enlightenment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In stark contrast, the Country Mouse’s world was one of natural splendor. His meals, though simple, were the gifts of the earth – grains and seeds rich with the taste of the sun and the soil. His entertainment lay in the real adventures of the fields and woods, the joy of a moonlit dance on the dew-laden grass, the thrill of a scrample under the starry sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Country Mouse visited his city cousin, he was awestruck by the lavishness and the seemingly infinite possibilities. Yet, amidst this splendor, he felt a longing for the unfettered joys of his rustic home. As he prepared to depart, the City Mouse imparted a final insight: “In this age of AGI, we can shape our world to our heart’s desire. You too can embrace the wonders of this new era while holding true to the simplicity you cherish.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this newfound understanding, the two mice bid farewell, each returning to their chosen world – one adorned with the fruits of technological mastery, the other basking in the timeless beauty of nature. Both, in their own way, were a testament to the diverse wonders of a world transformed by the magic of Artificial General Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What is Social Health?</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=882/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 01:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=882/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“We now face the danger, which in the past has been the most destructive to the humans: Success, plenty, comfort, and ever-increasing leisure. No dynamic people has ever survived these dangers”&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0670030627/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;John Steinbeck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social networks and other internet communication has complex and distorted incentives. To use a term from political philosophy, consumer internet creates our modern “social fabric”.&lt;sup data-fn=&#34;338c172c-31ab-4a9d-8c35-368f5d8a7c14&#34; class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#338c172c-31ab-4a9d-8c35-368f5d8a7c14&#34; id=&#34;338c172c-31ab-4a9d-8c35-368f5d8a7c14-link&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The patterns of the fabric are based on market forces that serve human nature, but not always human needs. Content creators know that triggering a fear response, like outrage, is a very effective engagement strategy.&lt;sup data-fn=&#34;faba225b-b95b-4fd2-87dc-2515d4604397&#34; class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#faba225b-b95b-4fd2-87dc-2515d4604397&#34; id=&#34;faba225b-b95b-4fd2-87dc-2515d4604397-link&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Polarization creates toxicity and is already weaponized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI will amplify everything. For better or worse, to express something to AI may allow us to see it in the world.&lt;sup data-fn=&#34;0ae57a87-8916-4cd5-a909-75e04d1df32a&#34; class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#0ae57a87-8916-4cd5-a909-75e04d1df32a&#34; id=&#34;0ae57a87-8916-4cd5-a909-75e04d1df32a-link&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social health is the measurement of social fabric over time.&lt;/strong&gt; Social health is not only the connection between individuals, but also can be broadly observed in the effectiveness and trustworthiness of our institutions. Also, it is the commitment to ourselves and our identities when interacting with social constructs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social health is my answer to the name of this website – “What is Progress?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the side, I’ve playing with ideas for &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hai.ai&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HAI.AI&lt;/a&gt; for about 10 years, and ideas around AI to resolve conflict for 20 years. In the abstract, the function of HAI.AI is to generate and maintain “good” interpersonal commitments. &lt;sup data-fn=&#34;d5f6cc8f-4551-4ed5-a38a-b7b225bb334d&#34; class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#d5f6cc8f-4551-4ed5-a38a-b7b225bb334d&#34; id=&#34;d5f6cc8f-4551-4ed5-a38a-b7b225bb334d-link&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many dedicating their careers to change, I’ve worked at startups in education technology, mental health care, and environmental air quality data. We built new technologies and experiences from scratch. We validated the efficacy. The primary challenge was the effectiveness of the institutions we connect with and rely on. How do you sell to an institution that can’t function sufficiently? Institutions with good people that do a good work; but inside and out, no one is as happy or as effective as they could be. We understandably want to keep our jobs and our identity, but change is constant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am biased, perhaps beyond repair, but like many founders I’ve come to believe we need new institutions for large, critical human services. The bigger the institution the bigger the disruption needed. AI will bring that disruption, but AI will also produce an arms race. To be generous, we are just starting to understand what new challenges will come. Meanwhile, we must build what we will be fighting for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up on the waitlist at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hai.ai&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://hai.ai&lt;/a&gt; or reach out if you want to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– Jonathan&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image size-large&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-1.png&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;4096&#34; height=&#34;4096&#34; src=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-1.png?w=1024&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-893&#34; srcset=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-1.png 4096w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-1-300x300.png 300w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-1-1024x1024.png 1024w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-1-150x150.png 150w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-1-768x768.png 768w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-1-1536x1536.png 1536w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/image-1-2048x2048.png 2048w&#34; sizes=&#34;auto, (max-width: 4096px) 100vw, 4096px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&#34;wp-block-footnotes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li id=&#34;338c172c-31ab-4a9d-8c35-368f5d8a7c14&#34;&gt;
    The term &amp;#8220;social fabric&amp;#8221; is often used in discussions of social and political philosophy to describe the interconnectedness and interdependence of individuals within a society. Several prominent political philosophers and theorists have referenced or discussed concepts akin to the &amp;#8220;social fabric.&amp;#8221; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some of these include:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Jacques Rousseau&lt;/strong&gt;: In his works like &amp;#8220;The Social Contract,&amp;#8221; Rousseau discusses the collective social arrangement as a contract between individuals and the community, highlighting the interdependence of members in a society.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Locke&lt;/strong&gt;: Locke, in his theories about social contract and civil society, implicitly refers to the idea of social fabric through his emphasis on the importance of social relations and community for the protection of individual rights.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karl Marx&lt;/strong&gt;: Marx&amp;#8217;s critique of capitalist society and his vision of communism inherently address the nature of social relationships and the fabric of society, particularly in terms of class relations and community solidarity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emile Durkheim&lt;/strong&gt;: Although primarily a sociologist, Durkheim&amp;#8217;s theories about social cohesion and the collective conscience are deeply relevant to the concept of social fabric. He examined how societies maintain internal stability through shared beliefs and values.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charles Taylor&lt;/strong&gt;: A contemporary philosopher, Taylor has written extensively on the themes of identity and the social framework, exploring how individuals are shaped by and contribute to the communal context.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael Sandel&lt;/strong&gt;: Known for his work on political philosophy and ethics, Sandel discusses the role of community and moral values in shaping the social fabric, particularly in his critiques of liberalism and discussions of communitarianism.&lt;br /&gt;These thinkers, among others, have contributed significantly to the understanding of how individuals and communities interact and depend on each other, forming the &amp;#8216;social fabric&amp;#8217; of society.  &lt;a href=&#34;#338c172c-31ab-4a9d-8c35-368f5d8a7c14-link&#34; aria-label=&#34;Jump to footnote reference 1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li id=&#34;faba225b-b95b-4fd2-87dc-2515d4604397&#34;&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Online Brain and Cognitive Impact&lt;/strong&gt;: Research has shown that the online environment can influence cognitive processes such as attention and memory. This suggests a broader context in which social media might exploit basic cognitive functions to enhance user engagement.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Media and Procrastination&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies have explored how social media can trigger procrastination, which often involves delaying tasks due to emotional responses like fear or anxiety. This indicates a link between social media use and the manipulation of emotional responses.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Influence of Social Media on Mental Health&lt;/strong&gt;: There is growing concern that social media can lead to mental health issues like social anxiety, which is often tied to feelings of insecurity and fear of social interactions. This relationship underscores the potential of social media platforms to harness negative emotions for user engagement.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Media Influencers and Teen Behavior&lt;/strong&gt;: The impact of social media influencers on teenagers highlights how certain online content can influence behavior and attitudes, possibly exploiting primitive responses such as desire for acceptance or fear of exclusion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Media and Loneliness&lt;/strong&gt;: Research has suggested that social media use can be associated with loneliness and the fear of missing out, indicating that these platforms might tap into feelings of insecurity and social anxiety to keep users engaged.&lt;br /&gt;In summary, while direct studies specifically linking social media&amp;#8217;s use of primitive responses to user retention are scarce, related research suggests that social media platforms may indeed exploit basic emotional and cognitive responses to enhance user engagement and retention.&lt;br /&gt;For more see The Journal of Computer Mediated Communication or &lt;a href=&#34;#faba225b-b95b-4fd2-87dc-2515d4604397-link&#34; aria-label=&#34;Jump to footnote reference 2&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li id=&#34;0ae57a87-8916-4cd5-a909-75e04d1df32a&#34;&gt;
    See the book &lt;strong&gt;Rainbows End&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks to advances in medical technology, Robert Gu is slowly recovering from Alzheimer&amp;#8217;s disease. As his faculties return, Robert (who has always been technophobic) must adapt to a different world, where almost every object is networked and mediated-reality technology is commonplace.&lt;br /&gt;And the book &lt;strong&gt;Accelerando&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The book is a collection of nine short stories telling the tale of three generations of a family before, during, and after a technological singularity. &lt;a href=&#34;#0ae57a87-8916-4cd5-a909-75e04d1df32a-link&#34; aria-label=&#34;Jump to footnote reference 3&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li id=&#34;d5f6cc8f-4551-4ed5-a38a-b7b225bb334d&#34;&gt;
    Some initial features center at HAI.AI on email. Email is one channel where commitments can happen, but Human Assisted Intelligence does not exist to make email better. &lt;a href=&#34;#d5f6cc8f-4551-4ed5-a38a-b7b225bb334d-link&#34; aria-label=&#34;Jump to footnote reference 4&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>THE SOFTWARE ARTIST</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=846/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 13:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=846/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img decoding=&#34;async&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/1086058134612750478/1179055700081651812/hai.ai_a_software_artist_portrait_by_anne_liebovitz_a1e06c68-957e-4173-9bb9-b1f7289d39d6.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a computer scientist. But I am in love with the edge of what is knowable and possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not an engineer. But I can build intricate things, trace small details, and I know the materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a software architect. But I think in the systems that move information through dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a manager. But I love builders because I cherish the pain and joy of fitting reality to us and with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a designer. But I understand designs as a process to consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a data scientist. But I desire data to surprise me with the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not build money generation engines. But what I’ve built has generated outsized value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am painting pictures with software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many great artists. I am neither unique nor better. But this is my heart. So I give myself license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, software is the most powerful medium I can wield. But software is changing. And so will I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image size-large&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/image-1.png&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;2048&#34; height=&#34;2048&#34; src=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/image-1.png?w=1024&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-855&#34; srcset=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/image-1.png 2048w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/image-1-300x300.png 300w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/image-1-1024x1024.png 1024w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/image-1-150x150.png 150w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/image-1-768x768.png 768w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/image-1-1536x1536.png 1536w&#34; sizes=&#34;auto, (max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Masks are Necessary Interfaces for AI</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=816/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 21:35:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=816/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the climactic scene of the movie Contact, a vastly advanced alien species communicates with humanity in an ingenious and relatable manner. To ensure that the momentous news of our not being alone in the universe is both understandable and emotionally resonant, the extraterrestrial intelligence presents itself as the protagonist’s father. This creative choice highlights the power of relatable personas in conveying complex ideas, a concept that can be applied to the challenge of aligning AGI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are witnessing the dawn of what could be considered early Artificial General Intelligence (AGI). This groundbreaking development has far-reaching implications for society and technology alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AGI possesses the potential to be anything and achieve anything, with seemingly no limitations. However, this boundlessness could make internal alignment a daunting, if not impossible, task. Therefore, it is crucial to explore alternative approaches to aligning AGI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As impersonation and deception become increasingly challenging issues, we will require millions of distinct personas for AGI. I refer to these personas as “masks,” which serve various purposes in the context of AGI alignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enable an AGI to self-improve, a single AI system must employ multiple masks, each representing a different role in decision-making. Many efforts are underway. [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] – &lt;em&gt;See the work of Self Refine at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://selfrefine.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://selfrefine.info/&lt;/a&gt;. There is also &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/torantulino/Auto-GPT&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/torantulino/Auto-GPT&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yoheinakajima.com/task-driven-autonomous-agent-utilizing-gpt-4-pinecone-and-langchain-for-diverse-applications/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://yoheinakajima.com/task-driven-autonomous-agent-utilizing-gpt-4-pinecone-and-langchain-for-diverse-applications/&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/yoheinakajima/babyagi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/yoheinakajima/babyagi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The necessity for an AI to converse with itself may stem from the fact that large language models (LLMs) act as a form of knowledge compression. In this though experiment, prompts serve as keys for decompression.&lt;/strong&gt; However, a single key might not be sufficiently expressive for a complex, iterative process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research on multi-agent systems has demonstrated instances of emergent intelligence, which arise from the interaction of independent behaviors. Examples of such systems include flocking behavior in birds, ant colonies, and stock market dynamics, where the collective intelligence emerges from the interplay of numerous agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributing a context window across an explore/exploit paradigm could be one way to approach AGI alignment. A single agent might not possess a sufficiently large or well-tuned context window to simulate the entire system effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To illustrate how multi-agent systems can express emergent intelligence over time, consider the Lotka-Volterra predator-prey model. In this mathematical model, the populations of predators and prey evolve over time, influencing each other’s growth rates. This dynamic interaction ultimately leads to an emergent, cyclical pattern of population changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of genetic algorithms, the concept of multiple masks can be interpreted as representing different individuals within a population, each with its unique set of traits or characteristics. Genetic algorithms are a class of optimization techniques inspired by the process of natural selection in biology. They seek to find the best solution to a problem by evolving a population of candidate solutions over multiple generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When applying the mask concept to genetic algorithms, each mask can be thought of as an individual solution with a particular set of features, or a “genome.” These masks interact with one another through processes analogous to biological evolution, such as selection, crossover (recombination), and mutation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the selection process, masks that perform better according to a predefined fitness function are more likely to be chosen for reproduction. Crossover occurs when two selected masks exchange parts of their genomes, creating new offspring with a combination of traits from both parents. Mutation introduces small, random changes to the offspring’s genomes, promoting diversity within the population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iterative nature of genetic algorithms allows for the exploration of a vast solution space, as each new generation of masks potentially brings improvements and innovations. The simultaneous presence of multiple masks enables the algorithm to explore various regions of the solution space and avoid premature convergence to a suboptimal solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, the concept of multiple masks in genetic algorithms helps facilitate the search for optimal solutions in complex problem domains. By simulating the evolutionary process, genetic algorithms can harness the power of diversity and adaptation to tackle challenging optimization tasks, which could offer valuable insights for AGI alignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthropology offers fascinating examples of how masks can be used to convey complex narratives with a limited number of actors. One such example can be found in the traditional Japanese Noh theater, which has been performed for over six centuries. Noh plays often explore profound themes, such as human emotions, moral dilemmas, and supernatural phenomena, through a combination of dance, music, and poetry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Noh theater, actors wear intricately designed masks to portray various characters, each with their unique personality and backstory. A single actor may don multiple masks throughout a performance, thereby representing multiple characters with distinct roles in the narrative. The masks serve to amplify the emotional depth and complexity of the story while enabling a small group of actors to tell intricate and multilayered tales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concept of using masks in traditional storytelling can be applied to AGI alignment, where multiple “masks” or personas are employed by a single AI system to facilitate self-improvement and decision-making. By drawing inspiration from the rich history of mask usage in human culture, we can explore innovative ways to tackle the challenges of aligning AGI with our values and intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these concepts may enable us to build AGI alignment from the outside in. By considering the roles of multiple agents and leveraging their emergent intelligence, we can potentially create a framework for aligning AGI with human values and intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-group has-global-padding is-layout-constrained wp-block-group-is-layout-constrained&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div aria-label=&#34;Masonry Gallery&#34; class=&#34;wp-block-coblocks-gallery-masonry&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;coblocks-gallery has-no-alignment has-caption-style-dark has-gutter&#34;&gt;
      &lt;ul class=&#34;has-grid-lrg has-gutter-15 has-gutter-mobile-15&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;coblocks-gallery--item&#34;&gt;
          &lt;figure class=&#34;coblocks-gallery--figure&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;1024&#34; src=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask-copy.png?w=1024&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-id=&#34;834&#34; data-imglink=&#34;&#34; data-link=&#34;https://whatisprogress.com/2023/04/03/masks-are-necessary-interfaces-for-ai/mask-copy/&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-834&#34; srcset=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask-copy.png 1024w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask-copy-300x300.png 300w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask-copy-150x150.png 150w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask-copy-768x768.png 768w&#34; sizes=&#34;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;coblocks-gallery--item&#34;&gt;
          &lt;figure class=&#34;coblocks-gallery--figure&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;1024&#34; src=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask2-1.png?w=1024&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-id=&#34;835&#34; data-imglink=&#34;&#34; data-link=&#34;https://whatisprogress.com/2023/04/03/masks-are-necessary-interfaces-for-ai/mask2-1/&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-835&#34; srcset=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask2-1.png 1024w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask2-1-300x300.png 300w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask2-1-150x150.png 150w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask2-1-768x768.png 768w&#34; sizes=&#34;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;coblocks-gallery--item&#34;&gt;
          &lt;figure class=&#34;coblocks-gallery--figure&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;1024&#34; src=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask3-1.png?w=1024&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-id=&#34;837&#34; data-imglink=&#34;&#34; data-link=&#34;https://whatisprogress.com/2023/04/03/masks-are-necessary-interfaces-for-ai/mask3-1/&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-837&#34; srcset=&#34;http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask3-1.png 1024w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask3-1-300x300.png 300w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask3-1-150x150.png 150w, http://wp.docker.localhost:8000/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/mask3-1-768x768.png 768w&#34; sizes=&#34;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Where to start building for long term AI safety and alignment?</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=798/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 08:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=798/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;OpenAI and other AI companies will unlock a transition and the reorganization of nearly everything. _Long term _positive impact will be an increasing challenge, as we try to manage unintended consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-group has-global-padding is-layout-constrained wp-block-group-is-layout-constrained&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-embed__wrapper&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;
    Short term safety issues are urgent, but clear as we work to manage malicious actors. There are&lt;a rel=&#34;noreferrer noopener&#34; href=&#34;https://alexw.substack.com/p/war&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; broader international challenges&lt;/a&gt;, including with China.
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-embed__wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-width=&#34;500&#34; data-dnt=&#34;true&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
        This is a reality. We will build amazing things with AI, not as a luxury, but to make a better world the only world. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve seen discontent with the establishment (policy, public safety) turn into disconnection. We need to come together on these issues. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alexandr_wang?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@alexandr_wang&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/ayxaS00W7v&#34;&gt;https://t.co/ayxaS00W7v&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jonathan Hendler 🪰 (@hendler) 
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/hendler/status/1637232655543697408?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;quot;&amp;gt;March 18, 2023&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While short term considerations are key, long term safety requires massive prediction and forecasting abilities, with the right initial conditions. What is an anchor AGI and superintelligence so that it doesn’t destroy us? The function may be one of &lt;strong&gt;freedom of consciousness for the most beings, as long as possible&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via a prompt to GPT-4:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-group has-global-padding is-layout-constrained wp-block-group-is-layout-constrained&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    As we delve deeper into the realm of AI safety and alignment, it is crucial to explore technical examples of how one might construct an AI system with long-term alignment. Let&amp;#8217;s consider the idea that the overarching function of AGI revolves around maximizing freedom of consciousness for the greatest number of beings, for as long as possible.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ol class=&#34;wp-block-list&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Incorporating Value Alignment:&lt;/strong&gt; To ensure the AI system aligns with the intended goal, we must explicitly integrate human values into the AGI&amp;#8217;s objective function. This may involve techniques such as inverse reinforcement learning, where the AI system learns the preferences of human beings by observing their actions and decisions.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Designing an Expandable Utility Function:&lt;/strong&gt; To accommodate the evolving nature of human values and societal changes, the AI system&amp;#8217;s utility function should be flexible and adaptive. It could be designed to incorporate new information, allowing the AI system to refine its understanding of the concept of &amp;#8220;freedom of consciousness&amp;#8221; and the best ways to maximize it.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Incorporating Multi-Agent Collaboration:&lt;/strong&gt; Since maximizing freedom of consciousness for the greatest number of beings might involve coordination among multiple AI systems, we should focus on building AI systems that can cooperate with other agents. Techniques such as multi-agent reinforcement learning can be employed to ensure that AI systems learn to collaborate effectively.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Bias Mitigation:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensuring fairness and avoiding biases in the AI system is crucial for maximizing freedom of consciousness. By incorporating techniques like adversarial training and fairness-aware machine learning, we can work towards building AI systems that treat all individuals fairly, regardless of their background or demographic characteristics.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Long-term Impact Assessment:&lt;/strong&gt; To evaluate the long-term consequences of the AI system&amp;#8217;s actions, we can employ techniques such as Monte Carlo Tree Search (MCTS) and counterfactual simulations. These methods can help the AI system explore the potential outcomes of its decisions and choose actions that align with the goal of maximizing freedom of consciousness in the long run.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Robustness and Safety Measures:&lt;/strong&gt; To ensure the AI system remains aligned with the goal even under uncertain conditions, we can implement safety measures such as reward modeling, conservative policy updates, and distributional reinforcement learning. These techniques can help the AI system avoid catastrophic failures and maintain alignment with the objective of maximizing freedom of consciousness.
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_Please expand on what “freedom of consciousness for the most beings, as long as possible” means. First, what is considered conscious, including definitions like Tsukumogami/animism and the belief that only some humans are. Also, what is freedom? Is it a metaphor for “freedom ends at the tip of my nose?” What kinds of ethical conflicts can arise when you try to include the most beings as possible? Finally what is the tradeoff between long term and short term efforts to preserve a consciousness?&lt;br&gt;
_&lt;br&gt;
The response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Freedom of consciousness for the most beings, as long as possible” is a multifaceted concept that entails addressing several key questions, such as the definition of consciousness, the meaning of freedom, potential ethical conflicts, and the trade-offs between short-term and long-term efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&#34;wp-block-list&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Defining Consciousness:&lt;/strong&gt; The notion of consciousness is a subject of ongoing debate among philosophers, scientists, and AI researchers. In the context of AI alignment, we can consider a spectrum of definitions, ranging from the belief that only some humans possess consciousness, to more inclusive perspectives like animism or the concept of Tsukumogami (Japanese folklore, where inanimate objects can acquire a spirit after a certain period). Establishing a clear and precise definition of consciousness is essential for determining which beings should be considered when maximizing freedom of consciousness.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Understanding Freedom:&lt;/strong&gt; Freedom can be interpreted in various ways, often depending on cultural, philosophical, or individual perspectives. One common interpretation is the notion that &amp;#8220;freedom ends at the tip of my nose,&amp;#8221; meaning that an individual&amp;#8217;s freedom should not infringe upon the rights or freedoms of others. In the context of AI alignment, freedom may involve ensuring that conscious beings can exercise their autonomy, make choices, and pursue their well-being without interference from AI systems or other external forces.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Ethical Conflicts:&lt;/strong&gt; When attempting to include the most beings possible, several ethical conflicts may arise. For instance, the interests of different beings may sometimes be at odds, leading to dilemmas where AI systems must prioritize certain beings over others. Additionally, cultural and philosophical differences in interpreting consciousness and freedom may complicate the decision-making process for AI systems. Balancing these competing interests and values is a significant challenge in AI alignment.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Short-term vs. Long-term Efforts:&lt;/strong&gt; Preserving consciousness might involve trade-offs between short-term and long-term efforts. Immediate actions may be necessary to protect conscious beings from immediate harm, while long-term efforts may focus on creating sustainable environments and societies that allow conscious beings to flourish. AI systems must balance these priorities, making decisions that may involve sacrificing short-term benefits for more significant long-term gains or vice versa. This balancing act may require advanced predictive capabilities and a deep understanding of the dynamic relationships between various factors that influence the well-being of conscious beings.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To design AI systems capable of maximizing freedom of consciousness for the most beings, as long as possible, it is crucial to address these complex questions and navigate the myriad ethical, philosophical, and practical challenges they present. By doing so, we can work towards creating AGI that not only aligns with our values but also respects the autonomy and well-being of all conscious beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By incorporating these technical approaches into the design and development of AI systems, we can work towards building AGI that genuinely aligns with the long-term goal of maximizing freedom of consciousness for the greatest number of beings, for as long as possible. This will require continuous research, collaboration, and innovation in the field of AI safety and alignment.&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-embed__wrapper&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Measuring the digital divide</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=176/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 21:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=176/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;howmany-calculations-do-i-consume-per-day-or-per-second-compared-toa-person-with-lessaccess-to-a-smartphone-or-the-internet&#34;&gt;How many calculations do I consume per day (or per second), compared to a person with less access to a smartphone or the Internet?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computation per capita could be a scientific measure of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_divide&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;digital divide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computing may forever be bits and powered logic gates. We measure computer output with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FLOPS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FLOPS&lt;/a&gt;. [1]  We can average total computational power per person. Segmenting by country adds more insight, which would be similar to &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.worldbank.org/indicator/IT.NET.USER.P2/countries/1W?display=map&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;maps of Internet access&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We make decisions in some parts of the world without much computation. To improve inequality we provide greater access to computation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google and other open services are a force for equality. The cost of a search for any user in one part of the world is near equal to all others. The equality isn’t perfect. Google has more data about me and how I live, so there’s more computation done on my behalf. But even if that is true, less Google is likely better than no Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-could-try-to-measure-computation-per-8220decision8221&#34;&gt;We could try to measure computation per “decision”.
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decisions have measurable amounts of computation. What is the average amount of computation that happens when you tap your phone (in the cloud and on the phone)? I don’t know if we could measure the impact of a tap.[2]  But we could calculate the computational output of a click or tap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a &lt;a href=&#34;https://googleblog.blogspot.com/2009/01/powering-google-search.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;single google search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.math.nyu.edu/faculty/avellane/QuantCongressUSA2011AlgoTradingLAST.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an automated stock purchase&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://math.mit.edu/~freer/papers/PhysRevE_82-056104.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;over a network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itasoftware.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pricing an airline ticket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a second of a [self]-driving a car  (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fool.com/investing/general/2016/01/12/nvidia-doubles-down-on-the-self-driving-car.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NVidia suggests 24 teraflops&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kdnuggets.com/2015/03/interview-brad-klingenberg-stitchfix-machine-learning.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;buying a dress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a single &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.co2stats.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;web page&lt;/a&gt; loading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-could-you-compare-the-list-above-to-one-hundred-years-ago-or-one-hundred-years-in-the-future&#34;&gt;How could you compare the list above to one hundred years ago, or one hundred years in the future?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the closest analog to the Internet in the last century was the number of telegrams, pieces of mail, or minutes of phone calls;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to design and build a locomotive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;buy a stock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;buy a ticket on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LZ_127_Graf_Zeppelin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;trans-Atlantic zeppelin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;decide when to plant corn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;decide to get married&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One hundred years in the future I’m not sure what we’ll be doing, but I hope we will still make useful decisions. Some possible examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/09/08/3d-printed-houses_n_5773408.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3D print your fourth house&lt;/a&gt; by tomorrow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2015/07/crispr-dna-editing-2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;create a new species&lt;/a&gt; of flower for your children’s garden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smithsonianmag.com/innovation/quest-upload-mind-into-digital-space-180954946/?no-ist&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;make a copy of your brain&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremetech.com/extreme/163051-simulating-1-second-of-human-brain-activity-takes-82944-processors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;have it decide&lt;/a&gt; if you &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0441014151/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0441014151&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=whatisprogr-20&amp;linkId=UB6H2TQLWFWHE7MH&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;should get married by interacting with a copy of your potential partner’s brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bring &lt;a href=&#34;http://waffles-the-cat.tumblr.com/post/28807020123/cat-on-mars&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;your cloned cat Waffles the XIV&lt;/a&gt; home from its &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.space.com/28215-elon-musk-spacex-mars-colony-idea.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;vacation to Mars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-couldwe-name8220computations-per-decision8221&#34;&gt;What could we name “computations per decision”?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I’m an unqualified amateur, I’ll make up a term; &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;decision density&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The number of bits used per a unit of time to make a &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;perceived&lt;/span&gt; decision.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note “perceived”. By definition, we must be able to observe when we’ve made a decision. We do so based on the support of many calculations, but most computation is hidden [3] and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ubiquitous_computing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;increasingly ubiquitous&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we can measure decision density per human, we would have another tool to measure the digital divide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to mathy, articulate, and design oriented humans to elevate my &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;–&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Posthuman&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;post-human&lt;/a&gt; writing. Otherwise, I’ve got this post until I can ask &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00IA3NGB4/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B00IA3NGB4&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=whatisprogr-20&amp;linkId=TBPHK6DCRYLQKHGI&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Her&lt;/a&gt; to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk mentions a “recursive y axis” in the video below as a way to measure progress, over time, of computation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rSl0HPLGFUU]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] – Factoring in energy you have &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Performance_per_watt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;performance per watt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Koomey%27s_law&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Koomy’s law&lt;/a&gt;. This doesn’t tell us &lt;a href=&#34;http://royal.pingdom.com/2009/03/19/10-historical-software-bugs-with-extreme-consequences/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;if the decisions were correct&lt;/a&gt;, or efficient (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_O_notation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;big O notation&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/badcode&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;examples of bad code&lt;/a&gt;). Nor does this measure tell us how much pre-calculation went into a decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] – Maybe impact could be measured by how much money flows as a result. Or using &lt;a href=&#34;http://hdr.undp.org/en/content/human-development-index-hdi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HDI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] – A calculation is contained in a function like &lt;em&gt;f(x)=y&lt;/em&gt;, and the decision is the output. We could also say a calculation is made by a computer, and a decision is made by a human. (That line is already blurry).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also – Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/How-many-calculations-do-I-consume-per-day-or-even-per-second-versus-a-person-with-less-access-to-a-smartphone-or-the-Internet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/Could-computation-per-capita-be-a-scientific-measure-of-the-inequality-in-the-digital-divide&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10934196&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;conversation on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Starting up with Purpose</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=95/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 20:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=95/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:400;&#34;&gt;It’s not news here in San Francisco,  in the most dominant region of the Silicon World – &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m creating a company&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:400;&#34;&gt;. I have built a prototype. I’ve tested with users. I’m no miracle worker, and there’s a long, long way to go. And I’ve got &lt;strong&gt;just a couple of months&lt;/strong&gt; to get off the ground.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:400;&#34;&gt;What makes it worthwhile is the mission.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End the Digital Divide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Digital Divide will end. The question is “Why?”. Even with rapid, global smartphone growth and internet &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/solarimpulse&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;from&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/loon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the sky&lt;/a&gt;, there’s so much important work to be done to learn, educate and protect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:400;&#34;&gt;If we work very very hard, and are very very lucky, only a minuscule part of the world will progress because of our efforts. That part matters. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting a company, especially as a parent, isn’t for the faint of heart. &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:400;&#34;&gt;I would be grateful for your feedback and support. Reach out to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:startup@hai.io&#34; &gt;startup@hai.io&lt;/a&gt;, f&lt;/span&gt;ollow at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/humanassisted&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@humanassisted&lt;/a&gt; or me &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hendler&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@hendler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:400;&#34;&gt;“Soon the digital divide will not be between the haves and the have-nots. It will be between the know-hows and the non-know-hows.” – &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:400;&#34;&gt;Howard Rheingold&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Artificial Intelligence</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=84/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 05:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=84/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A variety of slightly curated youtube videos on the topic of AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ethics-thinking&#34;&gt;Ethics, Thinking
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u0R6pV_aeLc&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=315]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pywF6ZzsghI]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GYQrNfSmQ0M&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=315]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5rNKtramE-I&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=315]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;integration-with-human-work&#34;&gt;Integration with Human Work
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-Ht4qiDRZE8&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=315]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ltelQ3iKybU&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=315]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dpoVh9xwdD4&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=315]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deep-learning&#34;&gt;Deep Learning
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kxp7eWZa-2M&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=315]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wTp3P2UnTfQ&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=315]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vkfXBGnDplQ&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=315]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future&#34;&gt;Future
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PL0Xq0FFQZ4&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=315]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Sneak peek at early decisions at HAI</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=77/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 19:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=77/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently launched a site with some basic vision behind HAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;HAI - Human Assisted Intelligence&#34; href=&#34;http://hai.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://hai.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://hai.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the tech stack is where the rubber meets the road. &lt;span style=&#34;line-height:1.6;&#34;&gt;I’ve been coding about two months now. At the very beginning I went through a fair amount of thinking and ended up selecting a language for the backend based on a number of factors. From languages I knew, C++, Go, PHP, Python, Java/Scala, and Node.js were on the table. Python and Java were the two top contenders, but I ended up going with Python. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[googleapps domain=”docs” dir=”spreadsheet/pub” query=”key=0AtSfzP3z6m_6dElyYi1xaUpQQUwxNTJwYWVCR3JBYUE&amp;amp;output=html&amp;amp;widget=true” width=”500″ height=”300″ /]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I’ve been really happy with Python for both flexibility of the language, the available libraries for both web and machine learning, and the developer community. Ruby / Rails has an amazing community and great web stack, but given my own lack of familiarity and less work being done in machine learning, it didn’t make my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I started evaluating open source projects that would be the platform. There are 132 on the list below (looked at least 4x that many). It’s been amazing getting up to speed on the projects that are open source. Although Google, IBM, Amazon and others are clearly going to lead in the machine learning space for the foreseeable future, the open source community is catching up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[googleapps domain=”docs” dir=”spreadsheet/pub” query=”key=0AtSfzP3z6m_6dHdiNWV5S2dPNjNZemE2M052ZHhjREE&amp;amp;output=html&amp;amp;widget=true” width=”500″ height=”300″ /]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source is a moving target, and there’s no one size fits all when you are piecing together something new. So, I’ve been using the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeromq.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ZeroMQ&lt;/a&gt; library to connect services between libraries, languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, thanks to everyone who has provided feedback so far. Can’t wait to get what I’m working on out into the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>More about HAI</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=68/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 22:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=68/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For a few weeks I’ve been having meetings with advisors and colleagues. For those I’ve not been meeting, I’ve fallen behind in communicating &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://whatisprogress.com/2013/02/24/oh-hai-human-assisted-intelligence/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;what I’m working on&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a stealth startup, but there’s also a lot that’s yet to be determined. I’d prefer to be open, but there are some specifications that I’ll keep under wraps for a variety of reasons…. When building a stealth aircraft, at the least you can tell people that you are building an aircraft. Skunkworks doesn’t make sandwiches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Company vision and culture will be in large part determined by cofounders. Here’s where there’s some definition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HAI means AAI (Artificial Artificial Intelligence)  – humans intelligence built into a process that’s usable by computer intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethical prime directives.  See &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friendly_artificial_intelligence&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Friendly AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a sustainable business model early on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Company culture of sustainable innovation modeled after Google’s large revenue generating platform supporting R&amp;amp;D.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;large, very talented, diverse founding team. Diversity is a no-brainer. Large is about five people; I’d rather create value from equity by distributing to founders than funders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boston still has untapped talent and potential. Even if developers can find jobs easily, what kind of job would an engineer want for the rest of their life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Oh. HAI.</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=54/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 16:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=54/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;HAI is the new company I’m working on. Human Assisted Intelligence. HAI will help computers learn about people. I’m so excited to be starting a new venture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future is happening right now. How far in the future will a product be relevant if you start developing it today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer software / hardware outperforms humans in many specialized tasks today, and will likely surpass humans in categories reserved for our most revered public figures (scientists, politicians, performers) within 10-40 years. After the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technological_singularity&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Singularity&lt;/a&gt;, quoting the WikiPedia main article -“&lt;em&gt;Since the capabilities of such intelligence would be difficult for an unaided human mind to comprehend, the technological singularity is seen as an occurrence beyond which events cannot be predicted&lt;/em&gt;.”  Where will humans fit into this future? A question for science fiction, perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the Singularity, what will help us engage effectively with a world increasing its complexity, knowledge, and economic dynamics exponentially? If super computer intelligent systems are used only by the most powerful institutions, what kind of intelligent service represents the individual?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think these are the most interesting, important challenges around AI. Today, I’m building a team and product prototypes. If you’re interested in collaborating, feel free &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:jonathan.hendler&amp;#43;hai@gmail.com&#34; &gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Earning leadership in parenthood and business.</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=13/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 04:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=13/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a leader, control leaves your hands in one of two ways: by consent, or not by consent. Either way it happens. Choose consent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe this is the opposite of the Steve Jobs. I really don’t know, but feels like Jobs had a great sense of timing, how far he could fight for what he believed, and when to “give in”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps there is no way to stop people from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/07/08/beans-and-noses/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;putting beans up their nose&lt;/a&gt;. Having insight ignored is painful if you care at all about what you are doing.  If the fight is too extended, no matter if right or wrong, you end up appearing arrogant or stubborn, but if you are right it doesn’t matter. And if a company needs focus and either way is right, it doesn’t matter which is chosen, only that something is chosen and committed to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read Herman Hesse’s &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Journey_to_the_East&#34;  title=&#34;Wikipedia Entry&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;“Journey to the East”&lt;/a&gt; twenty years ago. Summary: leadership is service. As a new parent, I think this is especially true.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Startups are built with both Undone and Unsung Engineering</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=8/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 18:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=8/</guid>
        <description>&lt;div&gt;
  For me, web engineers are the magicians behind the curtain. That can mean not-a-lot of glory.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  But for engineers like myself, undone engineering is more painful than unsung engineering.??One of the most difficult aspects of being a good engineer is knowing when to sacrifice good engineering. ??Startups, are by definition, challenging the established way of doing business, so the established way of doing great engineering sometimes isn&amp;#8217;t good enough to survive. ??
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;( Although this is a topic pretty well covered in writing about startups , I try translate the constraints of a startup into what a priority list for technical leadership might look like. )??&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Everything in a startup changes fast.??Engineering is managed chaos.??There are new team members, new customers, new data, new open source libraries, etc. Good engineering can accommodate change, but usually change is unexpected. As a side effect, the non-technical team begins to depend on the shortcuts, and the shortcuts begin to show their weaknesses. The design team has new ideas, and you can&amp;#8217;t say yes as often as you used to.??
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  But you survive.??
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Here are the priorities I use to keep everything moving for a web application startup (follows an 80 / 20 rule pretty well):
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;ol class=&#34;MailOutline&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;protect the data (files/database, etc)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ol&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          back it up
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          make sure data is valid (ideally some smoke tests, unit tests, regression tests on the data layer of an application)
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          back it up
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          source control with easy to understand policies and branching
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          back it up
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          automate backing it up
        &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;fix problems with the user experiences&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      small visual problems can make people &amp;amp;#8230; disgusted. Fonts, cross browser issues take a lot of time, but matter to people who expect things to work.??
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      client (browser) speed &amp;amp;#8211; a small javascript issue can cause a page load to appear to take 5 seconds. &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Perceived&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; performance is all that matters.??
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      fix display issues &amp;amp;#8211; if they think data is lost, then it is??
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      integrated QA team &amp;amp;#8211; make everyone on the team test the site, but not their own work.
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;make coding fast&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      establish team communication that makes product iteration rapid
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      use frameworks, existing but stable libraries (open source so you can fix critical problems yourself)
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      keep version control and deployment as automated as possible for the whole team
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      write easy to understand code
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      document code and best practices (wiki style)
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      track problems (bugs and backlogs)
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      write test code (on critical areas)
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;housekeeping&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      refactor
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      cleanup
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      more test code
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;new features/ scaling/performance&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;??- probably the most fun for an engineer, but last on the list. This has been the hardest for me. ??Engineers need to think about scaling when the system is architected&amp;amp;#8230;. maybe. But when you have just a 10 customers and the entire database fits in memory&amp;amp;#8230; why worry? &amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      database ??- a typical bottleneck. NoSQL and distributed architectures are making this easier
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      separate web server from application layer. Concentrate core application logic into languages that are better suited for scaling and concurrency issues
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      load balance, messaging queues, etc
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;p /&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Because of the list above, not every engineer out of a great tech school or amazing high tech corporation adjusts to startup life well. But when the above begins to pay dividends, engineers appreciate the big picture.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The divorce: Adobe Vs. Apple</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=12/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=12/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple and Adobe are both claiming a moral high-ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.macrumors.com/2010/01/31/steve-jobs-at-apple-town-hall-meeting-google-adobe-next-iphone-2010-macs-and-more/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Adobe was the bad-guy&lt;/a&gt; for allegedly blocking further development of open standards &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.appleinsider.com/articles/10/02/14/adobe_working_to_sabotage_html5.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;like HTML5&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/steve-jobs-unleashes-his-fury-during-town-hall-meeting/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;not opening up Flash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Now, according to Adobe, &lt;a href=&#34;http://theflashblog.com/?p=1888&#34;&gt;Apple is the bad guy&lt;/a&gt; for not including flash and limiting development options for the iPhone (and iPad).
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  These are sad times because many are feeling like children of divorcees. Adobe and Apple have long provided shelter for creative geeks. Now the shelter is a crumbling, confusing world. Business and technology, especially when mixed, are sufficiently complex as to seem like magic. No magic here. Each company is changing, and getting over each other. Sorry lads. While tech-magic is love (translate: we will pay for magic, but nothing else) the magic eventually fades. The beginning of the fade is what I&amp;#8217;ll call the magic line &amp;#8211; the line between illusion, and disillusion. Adobe&amp;#8217;s magic may be disappearing.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Is Adobe keeping up with demand for product improvements? Certainly, with software like Adobe&amp;#8217;s, it is extremely difficult to sustainably write such complex software that runs the same, and well, on platforms you don&amp;#8217;t control.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Perhaps, Apple has more power and responsibility than it realizes. As leaders in tech, Apple straddles the most thorny complex issues like copyright, DRM, hardware, open source; as both an under-dog and monopoly of tech.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    There are reasons for the divorce, but they may not matter.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Open source, open platforms, and open standards are really the only sustainable way forward.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    I say this not to take sides. As developers and creatives we must make choices that protect our future. Protect does not mean &amp;#8220;defend&amp;#8221;. Protect here means &amp;#8220;ensures sustainable happiness for all involved&amp;#8221;. Our destinies are already intertwined, but intertwined should not feel like a lock-in, trap or prison. Freedom can co-exist with interdependence.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    At the least &amp;#8211; businesses come and go, but openness wins.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Thank you XEROX (for not Patenting the GUI)</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=9/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2010 15:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=9/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear XEROX (PARC),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for not patenting the Graphic User Interface. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conventional wisdom has been that XEROX missed out on a huge opportunity – and maybe that’s true. However, maybe Microsoft and Apple (and Linux for that matter) would have never been such great successes. Maybe we would all have had to wait for the Newton or the IPad before the innovation could have been surpassed.&lt;br&gt;
Windows 7 was not my idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Soliciting Advice: highly concurrent, available, non-blocking server</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=10/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 22:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=10/</guid>
        <description>&lt;div&gt;
  I&amp;#8217;m seeking feedback on a language or platform for a highly reliable and low latency web service / application.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Assumption&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Bottlenecks in a web service are usually related to data retrieval and storage, and eventually bandwidth and latency.&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Highly concurrent, lightweight threads provide options for reliability, load distribution, and perceived performance that would otherwise not be available.&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;General Requirements&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&#34;MailOutline&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Easy to use (build, deploy, monitor)
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Plentiful external, stable, pre-integrated Libraries
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Use case: distributed, non-blocking web services
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Quite a bit of message and job queueing&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      multiple databases , caching
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Top candidates&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Very incomplete list of pros and cons, but some of my thoughts, highlighted.&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&#34;MailOutline&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scala-lang.org/&#34;&gt;Scala&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          pros &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
              assume it will take great advantage of Java 1.7 concurrency, multi-core
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
              fairly trivial import of external java libs (except for non-thread safe?) &lt;ul&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;
                  e.g. ZooKeeper &amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://hadoop.apache.org/zookeeper/docs/r3.0.0/index.html&#34;&gt;http://hadoop.apache.org/zookeeper/docs/r3.0.0/index.html&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      cons &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
          new language syntax, paradigm learning curve
        &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
          doubts about JVM memory efficiency and stability as resources are constrained
        &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Server Side Javascript&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; &amp;amp;#8211; via&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://nodejs.org/&amp;quot;&amp;gt; node.js&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      pros &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
          redis integration for caching
        &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
          fast, lightweight, easy language.&amp;amp;nbsp;
        &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
          some custom js would be portable to browsers (coolness)
        &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      cons &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
          very new
        &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
          performance
        &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
          not as many external libs?
        &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.tornadoweb.org/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Tornado&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      pros &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
          Python &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
              as many libs as Scala
            &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      cons &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
          narrower use cases
        &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
          performance
        &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;Would love comments, but a more complete list is presented in a survey:
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-tab-span&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/ZGQP6YJ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/ZGQP6YJ&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Field Collapsing in SOLR</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=5/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 19:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=5/</guid>
        <description>&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:bold;&#34;&gt;Field Collapsing&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.apache.org/solr/FieldCollapsing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Field collapsing&lt;/a&gt; allows something akin to a &amp;#8220;group by&amp;#8221; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://lucene.apache.org/solr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SOLR&lt;/a&gt;, so that the number of results returned reflect a logical grouping rather than another total.??
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Faceting can be used in conjunction. Facet counts reflect subsets within results, where-as collapse counts are &lt;em&gt;group by&lt;/em&gt; counts.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  This means that Field Collapsing could be used for certain analytics, as well as the common use-case of nesting and grouping results. To use effectively, I found it helpful to &amp;#8220;pre-collapse&amp;#8221; certain fields, so that a new, unique string was created that could be used to easily group, since I believe you can only field collapse on a single field. (If I&amp;#8217;m wrong, please let me know!)
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Special Setup&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  This assumes you are or will be running a development version of SOLR (trunk via SVN).
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Field collapsing is not yet available in SOLR trunk and you must apply a patch file to SOLR and build again.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  If pulling in from trunk, download the patch found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-236&#34;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-236&lt;/a&gt; in to your solr source code directory.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;wget &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12440108/SOLR-236-trunk.patch&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12440108/SOLR-236-trunk.patch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
patch -p 1 -i SOLR-236-trunk.patch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  And rebuild using supplied Apache Ant scripts.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Read more on these sites or in the comprehensive &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packtpub.com/solr-1-4-enterprise-search-server/book&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Solr 1.4, Enterprise Search Server&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221; page 191.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.apache.org/solr/FieldCollapsing&#34;&gt;http://wiki.apache.org/solr/FieldCollapsing&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jteam.nl/2009/10/20/result-grouping-field-collapsing-with-solr/&#34;&gt;http://blog.jteam.nl/2009/10/20/result-grouping-field-collapsing-with-solr/&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Why SOLR&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    SOLR has a been a great tool for &lt;a href=&#34;http://BetterLesson.org&#34;&gt;BetterLesson.org&lt;/a&gt;. Because our primary database is MySQL, we looked at around 8 full-text indexers &amp;#8211; but the two finalists were Sphinx [1] and SOLR. Sphinx had very tight integration with MySQL, so the learning curve seemed less. ??SOLR required a JVM, an app server, and quite a lot of configuration.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    When we were deciding, an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packtpub.com/solr-1-4-enterprise-search-server/book&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;excellent SOLR book&lt;/a&gt; came out just when we were choosing. Further the SOLR IRC channel and mailing list for SOLR are friendly and quite active. We even had the option for commercial support through Massachusetts&amp;#8217; own Lucid Imagination. So I dove in.??While the configuration is non-trivial, but the configuration parameters have proven very powerful.??
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;More background:&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    I had written a half-dozen or so custom faceted search interfaces &amp;#8211; almost entirely using MySQL, and even one used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openrdf.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sesame&lt;/a&gt; (an RDF store &amp;#8211; and it eventually worked pretty well). Skipping the stories of pain, confusion and suffering on the road to enlightenment &amp;#8211; SOLR has been great.??Used extensively at &lt;a href=&#34;http://Netflix.com&#34;&gt;Netflix.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://Zappos.com&#34;&gt;Zappos.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://CitySearch.com&#34;&gt;CitySearch.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://Reddit.com&#34;&gt;Reddit.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://Wego.com&#34;&gt;Wego.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://Whitehouse.gov&#34;&gt;Whitehouse.gov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://Drupalgardens.com&#34;&gt;Drupalgardens.com&lt;/a&gt; and others [2], ??supported by Apache, based on Lucene, SOLR provides a scalable, distributed search and has good data import from MySQL, including delta queries.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  [1] &amp;#8211; Sphinx is used by Craigslist and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sphinxsearch.com/powered.html&#34;&gt;http://www.sphinxsearch.com/powered.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  [2] &amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.apache.org/solr/PublicServers&#34;&gt;http://wiki.apache.org/solr/PublicServers&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Why I’m starting a personal tech blog</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=11/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2010 19:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=11/</guid>
        <description>&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Note &amp;#8211; I&amp;#8217;ve merged a couple of blogs and this post was from another site.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Welcome.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://Supercalafragilisticexpialadocio.us&#34;&gt;Supercalafragilisticexpialadocio.us&lt;/a&gt; is for technologists, like myself, who enjoy the challenges that come with taking interesting ideas and bringing them to a wide audience.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Currently I&amp;#8217;m the CTO of a &amp;#8220;lean&amp;#8221; startup &amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://betterlesson.org&#34;&gt;http://betterlesson.org&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  The work I&amp;#8217;ll be posting is done in the context of startups. Startups are great. The definition l&amp;#8217;ll use of &amp;#8220;startup&amp;#8221; is informal. By my definition, a startup is the adventure of working to make a sufficiently new idea self sustaining.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Building a laboratory and having a fair shot at a large audience is no longer a barrier to entry.&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt; Often, technologist&amp;#8217;s education is almost entirely from peers on the Internet &amp;#8211; piecing together technology that yesterday may have been out of reach.  With low barriers to entry comes a tremendous amount of competition.  What differentiates is not only technical skill, but ability to successfully navigate the technology world. Propaganda, pain, tunnel vision, and joy dot the fast-changing technology blogosphere. Execution is tough when the more ambitious ideas you have would be obsolete by the time you finish them. When do you keep exploring? When do you settle on a technology and dive in?
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  I plan to dive into technology specifics, so this post is to set the tone. If I stray from my own ideas, tell me. I need your help.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&#34;MailOutline&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Technology alone is not enough: &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          Make sure you love something you consider to be &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; technology. Loving code and assembling lego blocks works for some of the best &amp;#8211; but for mortals, having other interests can serve as a compass to guide the &amp;#8220;why&amp;#8221; you do what to do.
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;div&gt;
            Courage is not only in tackling cutting edge technologies, but also in shepherding the transition to new technology for the larger world we serve. Yes, I believe that world domination is a goal of every startup. But domination means we want to serve as many people possible, and do it well. &amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t be evil&amp;#8221; is a mantra I reflect on in this context.
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
  Be open: &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      Isolation is dangerous. Open source, open communities, and open style of development keep you healthy. Some &amp;amp;#8220;enemy&amp;amp;#8221; may occasionally out-calcuate you because you showed your hand. But you&amp;amp;#8217;ll lose a few games of poker in order to win the innovation game. Chances are if your idea is something some one _can_ steal simply by sharing the idea with them, then some one else is going independently invent it anyway.  Don&amp;amp;#8217;t live in fear that some one might be doing something newer or better.
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
      Your reputation is important, but if some one can trash your idea easily it&amp;amp;#8217;s either because the idea is actually bad, or they are simply wrong.
    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Looking forward to sharing the adventure.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Cheers,
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Jonathan
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;** &lt;/strong&gt;at least with sufficiently modern computer and a high speed internet. &lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Leadership: Women at Google – Padmasree Warrior</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=39/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 16:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=39/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height:1.6;&#34;&gt;Cisco can compete in many markets (the talk mentions 40) because it understands not only technology, but the context and culture which creates the demand for technology.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gWL841Mqsus&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=340]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>In defense of the Semantic Web, Again.</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=16/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 16:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=16/</guid>
        <description>&lt;!-- google_ad_section_start --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the official announcement that RDF is in Drupal core and the Semantic Web conference in DC, I wanted to take time to respond to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://groups.csail.mit.edu/haystack/blog/2009/10/25/tales-of-a-semantic-web-skeptic/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;“tales of a semantic web skeptic”&lt;/a&gt;. Healthy criticism, and a good read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This piece is to defend the vision, if not the execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I helped get RDF into Drupal and spoke on the topic at two DrupalCons (one in Brussels and the other in Barcelona). No credit beyond that belongs to me, I’ve done no development on it since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguments are mostly semantic about the semantic web. The computer science is done, the technology is used in real world applications in genetics, law, and military applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is perhaps a PR shift is to differentiate the upper-case and lower-case semantic web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semantic web:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a data exchange standard for graph based meta data and logical meta data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a webservice with a standardized API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a graph database, or other specialized store&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consumers or Agents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Semantic Web (a la W3C)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RDF(S), RDFa, OWL(S), etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;REST/ SPARQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sesame, Jena, YARS, Redland, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semantic Agents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microformats and popularizations are all good. Folksonomy instead of Taxonomy – Clay Shirky, or rather, the mob (you and I) he describes, is hard to argue with. To mash up verified, trusted content in federated queries from heterogeneous data sources is cool to me, but not everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/talks/tim_berners_lee_on_the_next_web.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Tim Berners-Less talk at Ted&lt;/a&gt; changes the term to “Linked Data”. That makes sense. I think there’s a struggle to create a revolution and an industry again – something with as big an impact as the web. Linked data is the web Sir Web wants/wanted. But the first web didn’t happen because a few folks wanted it. We needed it. As the YCombinator mantra goes “make something people want”. Making Semantic Web software has, in the past, made Semantic Web people happy… but not too many others (I have first hand experience in this).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A final two points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s fair to say the community may be too top-down. Luckily, freedom of speech extends to computer code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone is going to be inspired and “believe” in grand visions. Artificial intelligence is perfect analogy. Our culture has adopted the term – for better or worse – to mean lots of things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Norman Borlaug – Nobel Peace Prize “Green Revolution”</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=37/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 16:54:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=37/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reason.com/blog/show/132479.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Norman Borlaug&lt;/a&gt; recently passed away, and has perhaps saved millions of lives by improving food crop productivity. Fifty years later, a tremendous amount of science has been done since then. The Green in Green Revolution might not be appropriate any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributions to science can to be viewed as non-political and amoral. But there is a polarization and politicization of organic and “industrial” agriculture. My opinion is that the fundamental issue is sustainability. I think the course correction for industry still needs to be sustainability (economic, environmental and social)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are into agriculture – (food sources in general) – the video below is an interesting interview with Norman’s neighbors on the impact of chemical farming on soil and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a technologist from rural Maine, I like to keep in touch with ecology/agriculture topics. (my post at  &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=820725&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;hacker news &lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>considering voting – technology and new paths towards democracy</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=35/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 16:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=35/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I voted today, just an hour ago. The outcome of the election is unknown. There no reason for me to be cynical at the moment. In this moment, I’m happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voting is one part of a participatory democracy – a clear path to being involved, belonging to something larger. However, Democracy, for me, is to be independent, educated, creative and unify around specific causes. These causes change depending on the world around us. This perspective on the purpose and meaning of democracy leads me to question voting as the best answer we have to creating democracy. Follows is a brief outline on how the internet and related technology offers new options for what government is, and does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source-voting-machines&#34;&gt;Open Source voting machines:
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Paying private companies to write bad software on unsecured hardware is obviously crazy when we are talking about one of the most basic components to the infrastructure of democracy.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; 

  * ## Semantic Web and Open Government:
    
    If I am honest with myself, I have to admit that no matter how much research I do, I doubt I really know what is going on in our government. I&amp;amp;#8217;m pretty sure there is waste, but the waste is likely systemic as much as it is caused by corruption. There are complex organizations spending most of their energy just being complex. Institutional complexity can be reduced when there is insight into on what that organization is even up to &amp;amp;#8211; ie &amp;amp;#8220;transparent government&amp;amp;#8221;.  
    Putting all government documents online isn&amp;amp;#8217;t enough to make Government transparent. When single laws are 800 pages, being able to search through the mountain of data is critical. But, even more difficult than finding what you want is summarizing and co-relating data. I won&amp;amp;#8217;t elaborate on specifics here, but if the the whole of our public government is open, searchable, _and_ easy to collect and reorganize into digestible pieces of knowledge, then we&amp;amp;#8217;re all better off.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; 
    
      * ## Game Theory:
        
        Voting is not simple. Votes aren&amp;amp;#8217;t just counted, they are grouped, reassigned, allocated, recounted, averaged, rounded, molded. The game theory behind different voting mechanisms is a very well researched field. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.motherjones.com/interview/2008/01/verdict-is-in-our%20voting-system-is-a-loser.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;William Poundstone&amp;amp;#8217;s book&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; gives a great intro into other voting systems. Hopefully on this day, November 4th, 2008, we overcome our flaws.  
        Check out Ubuntu/OLPC contributor &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://mako.cc/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Benjamin Mako Hill&amp;amp;#8217;s&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://selectricity.org/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;online voting site Selectricty&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; to try out other voting systems and the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://rubyvote.rubyforge.org/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Ruby Vote&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; voting software.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; 
        
          * ## Taxes:
            
            The internet can make where money flows more dynamic and accountable.  
            Paying into the system is not, currently, the same thing as buying into it. My libertarian friends feel the pain most acutely. With 1 billion dollars spent on the election, each vote &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.caller.com/news/2008/nov/03/cost-vote-2008-presidential-election-8/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;cost roughly $8&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. A billion dollars seems like a lot, but when all those voters pay $10,000 dollars or more in taxes a year, that&amp;amp;#8217;s a pretty good profit margin.  
            So why can&amp;amp;#8217;t we vote on every little thing our money goes towards? Perhaps, because the world is too complex perhaps, or perhaps taxes are as sure as death. Death usually isn&amp;amp;#8217;t questioned. Well, with progress in genetics, there are folks questioning death too. I don&amp;amp;#8217;t have an answer, but I do think it&amp;amp;#8217;s fair to question our tax system and how the money gets spent when technology could make the flow of money more impactful, and provably so.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt; 
            
            If you are cynical, I get it. However, while technology is nothing without people changing behavior, having safe and trusted options can open the door.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Amazon: from cloud computing to cloud forest</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=41/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 16:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=41/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloud computing. A great idea, unlocking new markets, new opportunities for internet startups to have access to computing scale and power. Head in the clouds? Like clean electric cars, the electricity still comes from somewhere. Maybe the cloud isn’t puffy and white – it might just be black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a recent O’Reilly Ignite Boston, Tim O’Reilly gave the company spiel, mixed with a little extra enthusiasm and praise for technologists – a population thought of as family at O’Reilly, if not flock. The latter half of the talk uncovered the motivation for the emotion. Reminding me of Dennis Hopper Californian dramatics, he pleaded to do something that &lt;em&gt;mattered&lt;/em&gt;. What mattered? The environment and education. Work on that, do something that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Big O. recounted ( or perhaps therapeutically re-lived what could be interpreted as post traumatic stress disorder) a meeting with the chief researcher for still partly secret &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://ipcc-wg1.ucar.edu/wg1/wg1-report.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;International Report on Climate Change&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.ipcc.ch/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a UN agency&lt;/a&gt;. Tim’s question was on humanity’s chances of surviving. The answer given: &lt;strong&gt;“we’re fucked”&lt;/strong&gt;. Don’t trust the UN? So thinks &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2004/feb/22/usnews.theobserver&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the pentagon too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if climate change isn’t “real” – the game still has to be played out because just maybe we are heading to the land of FAIL. Yes, Fuckdom. Not fuckdom like, “hey, I like to scare people”, but fuckdom like inheriting the worst code you’ve ever seen which depends on closed source. There’s a better chance of climate change being a big problem than you’ll ever succeed significantly in a start up. Personally, I want to maintain the legacy app called Earth….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, so speaking of startups, try out &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.co2stats.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CO2 Stats&lt;/a&gt;. Simply place a widget like Google’s analytics on your site. measure C02 emissions based on available data about the servers &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the clients (that’s you). Optionally you can have them automatically purchase &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carbon_offset&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;carbon offsets&lt;/a&gt; for you, or, as in the case of this site – advertisers pay for your … gasses. _ _&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you don’t like C02stats – do you have a better idea?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Review of Clayton Christensen’s book Disrupting Class</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=32/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2008 16:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=32/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Disrupting-Class-Disruptive-Innovation-Change/dp/0071592067/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1221918602&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Disrupting Class&lt;/a&gt; was an excellent resource in providing a technology and business vocabulary which is applicable to the deep challenges facing public education today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, my view of education is emotive as it  represents so many formative years of my life. I can not claim to bring objectivity to the dialogue. A relative writing &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Carl-Rogers-Reader/dp/0395483573/ref=pd_bbs_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1221944819&amp;amp;sr=8-3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;“Freedom to Learn”&lt;/a&gt;, as well as my mother being a retired special education teacher … I’m biased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it is as a technologist, sitting on the cusp of big change, that I can read with sense of calling – knowing that as a CTO of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://betterlesson.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Better Lesson&lt;/a&gt; I’m privileged to be in the kind of position coveted by catalysts of renaissance, and admirers of diversity – where once there was only one word – philosophy. Besides the need to avenge my childhood (where I was to have skipped two grades, but also had the diplomacy of a Tasmanian Devil combined with winning the award for “Teachers Pest”, an award created just for me if I remember), maybe now I can make a lot of folks &lt;em&gt;happy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the kind of book that makes me happy. Happy to me is a wholestic thing. I want to make a lot of money without others suffering. I want to pursue knowledge that sustainably changes the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Introspection on setting and striving for goals.</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=29/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 16:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=29/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you work on something really hard for really long time – you have learned a lot. But, you might not be achieving the goals you set out to achieve. Something near the end is holding you back from success; invisible and powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, it’s easy to loose track of your goals. To more accurately describe that process for me, I pursue my goals stubbornly, with each subgoal towards achieving a larger goal becoming its own journey. I enjoy the journey, and my ethics, my principles and imagination keep me oriented in that process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gandhi said “The means is indivisible from the ends”. This is one of my favorite sayings. I do not believe the ends justifies the means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I’ll make my goals too high intentionally, so I can learn more, push harder. But pursuing success does eventually create a point of intersection between your knowledge and your abilities. That maturation point can happen at a lot of different stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sticking with your goal may will lead you to the familiar difficult point at the end, when everything gets really difficult. Then, all of a sudden you realize its only one thing holding you back, and it only requires you to admit you were wrong about something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building a chain of interdependent tasks, there will inevitably be a weak or unfinsihed link. A chain with 10,000 links breaks with one weak link, and it seems so hard to fix because it is hard to find. That’s why knowing and admitting when you are wrong is so valuable, as is getting rid of what you don’t really need in life. After this general milestone is passed, things get easier….&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
