<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Education on </title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/tags/education/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Education on </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2008 16:45:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Review of Clayton Christensen’s book Disrupting Class</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/?p=32/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2008 16:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>jonathan.hendler&#43;whatisprogress@gmail.com (Jonathan Hendler)</author>
        <guid>//localhost:1313/?p=32/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Disrupting-Class-Disruptive-Innovation-Change/dp/0071592067/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1221918602&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Disrupting Class&lt;/a&gt; was an excellent resource in providing a technology and business vocabulary which is applicable to the deep challenges facing public education today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, my view of education is emotive as it  represents so many formative years of my life. I can not claim to bring objectivity to the dialogue. A relative writing &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Carl-Rogers-Reader/dp/0395483573/ref=pd_bbs_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1221944819&amp;amp;sr=8-3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;“Freedom to Learn”&lt;/a&gt;, as well as my mother being a retired special education teacher … I’m biased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it is as a technologist, sitting on the cusp of big change, that I can read with sense of calling – knowing that as a CTO of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://betterlesson.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Better Lesson&lt;/a&gt; I’m privileged to be in the kind of position coveted by catalysts of renaissance, and admirers of diversity – where once there was only one word – philosophy. Besides the need to avenge my childhood (where I was to have skipped two grades, but also had the diplomacy of a Tasmanian Devil combined with winning the award for “Teachers Pest”, an award created just for me if I remember), maybe now I can make a lot of folks &lt;em&gt;happy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the kind of book that makes me happy. Happy to me is a wholestic thing. I want to make a lot of money without others suffering. I want to pursue knowledge that sustainably changes the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
